hey g'day
today's the 8th of april 2012.
peter stevens with my name and some of
you may have seen some of our other
videos
um what i'd like to show you
are just some what i refer to as
rattlesnake egg magnets
and these are just kids toys so you get
them and you
throw them in there and catch them and
they make this funny noise
they also come in different sizes
uh little ones big ones round ones
either
and uh great fun to play with so
you can hear them rattle quite nicely
and the other ones
they're just separated slightly and
thrown into the air
they spring around a fair bit what
they are is let me show you
is that they have a way
of coming together so this would be
normally
a north and a south that's in attraction
these particular ones are in the center
and when you turn at 90 degrees they
actually come apart
so that's the unusual
way that these particular magnets
align so they're aligned through the
middle
and if i turn one at 90 degrees
it'll push apart from the other it just
doesn't won't go together
so as soon as you you you bring it into
that regard it'll it'll try to equalize
and balance itself
which is absolutely fantastic so the
science of what we're doing
is probably best referred to by dr
walter russell or dr walter and his wife
leo russell and they they came up with a
book
called the sequence of light the secret
of light
and in that they describe
electricity magnetism
and just some of the fantastic ways
that everything has either a positive or
negative charge
these are some of the other formats
and there happens to be the periodic
tables
as per dr walter russell in 1921
so he came up with this spiral graph
that showed
all of the elements in the world
sorry quite not quite he did mention
some
showed where they were but called them
unknown so he left room for us to find
them
so from 1921 90 years ago
he actually discovered a lot of the
elements
and this spiral graph shows where all
the inert gases are
shows where each different charge is
whether it's a positive a negative
charge
there are four positives and four
negatives
three two one zero if it's a zero it's
an inert gas
and these are like compression lines
or octaves
octaves are the sound of music he also
referred
to music as being some of the
fields of interest
as to why things work so within this
book
are several diagrams a lot of
wonderful aspects of cube or body center
cube structures
which show the the actual cube formation
and just how each charge
comes across but you'll notice that it
always remains in balance
like you heard before with the
resonation of the of the discs
when they're in vibration they actually
finally reach a point of balance
so this is what dr walter russell was
showing
so this this particular book was written
i think in 1945
or 1947 but in in that vicinity so these
are the cube
structures these are all the crystal
structures that he could see
and what actually was going on so
talking about crystal structures
so this is magnetic fields and electric
induction
and the gravity or convective
how it increases in fields field
strength
what we're seeing here is what he
referred to as positive and negative
and these fields or arcs of angles
actually show the south pole and the
north pole
the north pole i believe is actually
like a
a sphere and it becomes even
more and more increasing so here's the
earth as you
normally see it north pole
facing directly up but when you get to
the north pole
you're in fact going south
because the polarity actually changes so
these are
the types of fields and field strengths
of what we're doing so we're doing
atmospheric ionization research
so we're spinning vortices in the air
and we're causing rain
and you can see some of our stuff on
weathercreation.com
so these are how magnetic fields and
forces
spiral in past each other and or push
apart
so they push apart far enough that'll
actually make a tornado
so let me show you some you can see
discs here
and i've actually got some disc magnets
which i just like to show you
how here are tornadoes for instance
these are magnetic cones that are pushed
apart
far enough and they'll actually leave
one within the earth and one in the
atmosphere
so this is how the fields can be altered
i believe
we can spiral the air spiral the the
light of the sun
back in and form tornadoes if you like
or unwind
tornadoes uh unwind cyclones and
hurricanes and typhoons or if you need
one we can produce one
so it's all a bit of fun that's the
secret of light by dr walter
now let me show you as i said we've got
this magnet
so here's just a couple of washers
i just want to show you that the magnet
and the washer go together the washer
and the washer there's no attraction
whatsoever
but i can i can pull this away fairly
fairly
readily but if i put it together like
that
and i attach another
washer the washers are now
magnetic magnetized
very difficult to pull it apart ah
but let's say i've got some other
magnets and i just happen to have a
couple here
i'll just check that just want to see if
i'm in repelling or or attraction so
just to see what these want to do and
they don't want to go together so
they're really
pushing apart so if i turn that over
that will attract
um and that that's why those
two there are together they're in
attraction
and i'll try and just pull these apart
it's very tough
i'm not that tough well i did out of a
couple of weak decks of flying they do
come
apart
and i'll just put that there
this is a stainless steel washer and
it's very lightly attracted to it
but because they're repulsing
they don't go together you can push them
together but they immediately just
pull apart so you know it's true
similar fields repel
and all the light fields repel and
unlike
fields attract so if i turn this over
they'll come together and that that's
what you normally expect with magnets
okay so
you're all happy with that i have so
i'll just pull these apart one more time
and we'll we'll just
turn turn don't need to turn the washer
over but i'll just turn the repulsion
over
and i'll i'll just add a different type
of washer
that's stainless again sorry i'm just
looking for my
trusty
other um
over here i'll just use a longer shaft
just to show you
um these
magnets are in repulsion
and that's that's pretty normal
so they they go apart and they go apart
quite nicely the the unusual thing with
atmospheric ionization is that we like
to do things slightly different
and get them to attract so that they
actually
form and form an attraction but normally
this would be in repulsion
straight away so we've overcome the
repelling nature of the
magnet and what we've also done is that
we've actually increased the power
that they come apart
they should love it when they lie to you
so it would in fact go off the end of
this rod
the rod's approximately uh three foot
length
or if you like 900
millimeters or 90 centimeters
so that's its normal
repelling nature the the distance
um we should measure it for you so that
you've got
comprehension of what we're
doing there so that's three and a half
inches
in the old star or
coming from there hey
attention just love filming all right
this one
just stop that play hello